

Project Description Secure File Transfer and Storage in cloud computing using Hybrid Cryptographic Algorithms such Blowfish Algorithm, Rivest Cipher (RC6) Algorithm. Advanced

Roles & Responsibilities

Pension Management System Jr. Full Stack Engineer - 3 Months (Mar-2022 - Jun 2022)

MySQL as Back end technologies. Also Involved in testing the complete flow using cloud computing and cryptographic algorithms. Also Involved in creating Report and Paper Presentation documentations required for this project. Also attended Paper presentation and project display events such "Green Mechatronics System -

GREEMS 2K20" event held in my college.

ANSI SQL 📲 JDBC Core Java Java Server Pages

Encryption Standard (AES) Algorithm and Least Significant Bit Algorithm (LSB) and this project uses JSP servlets as Front End and Java & MySQL as Back end.

Worked as a Co Developer in gathering requirements, designing and developing Hybrid Cryptographic Algorithms using JSP servlets as Front End and Java &

Project Description This project is based on the managing pension related operations such as registering the user, retrieving the pension scheme and details, calculating pension

Skills used for Pension Management System

Digital Medical Records App Developer - 3 Months (Jul-2020 - Sep 2020)

Tweet App | Full Stack Engineer - 2 Months (Jun-2022 - Sep 2022)

Skills used for Secure File Transfer Cloud Based App

Roles & Responsibilities

Accreditation).

Working as a full stack developer mainly involved in gathering requirements, designing and developing Reactive Full Stack Application which is developed using Angular as front end web application with JWT tokenization and Spring Security for application web security and MySQL and JPA repository as back end and spring boot & microservices along with eureka naming server and config servers and REST web services for developing the business logics and Junit for End to End Unit Testing. Also used Amazon cloud services such as Amazon EC2, Amazon ElasticBeanStalk and Amazon S3 bucket

Java 8

Angular JS

AWS EC2

amount based on the bank types and pension schemes using angular as front end and MySQL as back end and spring boot & microservices and REST web services

for developing the business logics. This project is developed as part of Cognizant's GENC Digital Honors Program for Java Full Stack Engineer Role (FSE 0

Spring Core Microservices

Project Description This project is based on the managing medical prescriptions and records which includes registering the patient, retrieving the patient and consultant details and adding, editing the patient prescriptions using JSP as front end and MySQL as back end and spring boot and REST web services for developing the business logics.

Core Java

developing the business logics. Also involved end to end unit testing using Junit. This application is developed as part of a code hackathon conducted by ADM-CMT of Cognizant Technology Solutions.

Roles & Responsibilities

Skills used for Digital Medical Records App JDBC Spring Core Java Server Pages Java 8 **ANSI SQL** Core Java

Worked as Java developer involved gathering the requirements, designing and developing the Medical Record Management application using JSP as front end and

Spring Security for application web security and MySQL and as back end and Spring boot, Spring JPA Repository, JDBC Template and REST web services for

This project is based on the Twitter app where creating a new tweet, likes, comments for that tweet can be done by multiple users. This full stack application uses angular as front end and Mongo DB as back end and spring boot & microservices and REST web services for developing the business logics. This project is

developed as part of Cognizant's GENC Digital Honors Program for Java Full Stack Engineer Role (FSE 1 Accreditation).

AWS EC2

Java 8

Worked as a full stack developer mainly involved in gathering requirements, designing and developing Reactive Full Stack Application which is developed using

Skills used for Tweet App

••00

Cassandra

Roles & Responsibilities

Project Description

Angular as front end web application with JWT tokenization and Spring Security for application web security and MongoDB and Apache Cassandra as back end and spring boot & microservices along with eureka naming server and config servers and REST web services for developing the business logics and Junit for End to End Unit Testing. Also used Amazon cloud services such as Amazon EC2, Amazon ElasticBeanStalk and Amazon S3 bucket for deploying the application in AWS cloud.

Career Highlights

Certified in NPTEL Course: "Information Security - IV". (Jan 2018 - Mar 2018). 3rd position in Zone-II State Level Inter Collegiate Quiz Competition conducted by

Angular JS

Microservices

Kafka

Spring Core

Indira Gandhi Centre for Atomic Research, Kalpakkam at CIET, Coimbatore. Sports: - Runners in CEHA Hockey Tournament in association with CDHA at Suguna

Core Java

College of Engineering, Coimbatore (Sep 2022) - Runners in Anna University Zonal Level Hockey Tournament. (2017-2018) - Second Runners in Anna University Zonal Level Hockey Tournament. (2018-2019) & (2019-2020) - Winners in MCET Hockey Trophy 2020 and Second Runners in 2019. Position and Responsibility: Organized a dance program in International World Record Cultural Event for School students by Elite Circle at Codissia Hall, Coimbatore. - Hockey Team Captain, Hindusthan College of Engineering & Technology. (2017-2020) - SPL, Swami Vivekananda Matric Hr.Sec.School. (2014-2016).

Education

Graduation

Bachelor of Engineering প্র

05/20/2020

For Cognizant internal circulation only